The following content is provided under a Creative
广告素材下提供了以下内容
Commons license.
普通许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare
continue to offer high quality educational resources for free.
继续免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: Today we're going to introduce graph search
教授：今天我们将介绍图形搜索
in general and talk about one algorithm, which
一般来说，谈论一种算法，
is breadth-first search, and understand how in principle you
是广度优先的搜索，并了解原则上
can solve a puzzle like the Rubik's Cube.
可以解决魔方之类的难题。
So before I get to Rubik's Cubes let
所以在我进入魔方之前
me remind you of some basic stuff about graphs.
我提醒您一些有关图的基本知识。
Or I can tell you to start out with, graph search is
或者我可以告诉您开始时，图形搜索是
about exploring a graph.
关于探索图。
And there's many different notions of exploring a graph.
探索图有许多不同的概念。
Maybe I give you some node in a graph, s,
也许我给你图中的某个节点s
and some other node in a graph, t,
图中的其他节点t
and I'd like to find a path that's
我想找到一条
going to represent a problem like I give you
代表我给你的问题
a particular state of a Rubik's Cube and I want to know
魔方的特定状态，我想知道
is there some path that gets me into a solved state?
有什么方法可以使我进入已解决状态？
Do I really want to solve this on stage?
我真的要在舞台上解决这个问题吗？
What the hell?
我勒个去？
We started.
我们开始了。
So this is a particularly easy state to solve,
因此，这是一种特别容易解决的状态，
which is why I set up this way.
这就是为什么我这样设置的原因。
All right, so there you go.
好吧，那您就去了。
Seven by seven by seven Rubik's Cube solved in 10 seconds.
七乘七乘七的魔方在10秒内解决。
Amazing.
惊人。
New world record.
新的世界纪录。
So you're given some initial state of the Rubik's Cube.
因此，您已经获得了魔方的一些初始状态。
You're given the targets that you
您得到的目标是
know what solved looks like.
知道解决的方式。
You want to find this path.
您想找到此路径。
Maybe you want to find all paths from s.
也许您想找到s的所有路径。
Maybe you just want to explore all the nodes
也许您只想探索所有节点
in a graph you can reach from s.
在图中可以从s到达。
Maybe you want to explore all the nodes in a graph or maybe
也许您想探索图中的所有节点，或者
all the edges in a graph.
图中的所有边。
These are all exploration problems.
这些都是探索问题。
They're all going to be solved by algorithms
它们都将由算法解决
from this class and next class.
从这个班和下一个班
So before we go further though, I
所以在继续之前，我
should remind you what a graph is
应该提醒您什么是图形
and sort of basic features of graphs
图的基本特征
that we're going to be using.
我们将要使用的。
This is also 6042 material so you should know it very well.
这也是6042的材料，因此您应该非常了解它。
If you don't, there's an appendix
如果没有，则有一个附录
in the textbook about it.
在有关它的教科书中。
We have a set of vertices.
我们有一组顶点。
We have a set of edges.
我们有一组优势。
Edges are either unordered pairs--
边要么是无序对-
some sets of two items--
一些两件套
or ordered pairs.
或有序对。
In this case, we call the graph undirected.
在这种情况下，我们称该图为无向图。
In this case, we call the graph directed.
在这种情况下，我们称其为有向图。
Usually, there's only one type.
通常，只有一种类型。
Either all the edges are directed
所有边缘都指向
or all the edges are undirected.
或所有边缘都是无向的。
There is a study of graphs that have both,
有一项对图的研究，
but we are not doing that here.
但是我们不在这里做。
Some simple examples.
一些简单的例子。
Here is a graph.
这是一张图。
This is an undirected graph.
这是无向图。
This is a directed graph.
这是有向图。
The set of vertices here is a, b, c, d.
这里的一组顶点是a，b，c，d。
The set of vertices here is a, b, c.
这里的一组顶点是a，b，c。
The set of edges here is--
这里的边集是-
E is going to be things like a, b; b, c; c, d--
E将会是a，b之类的东西； b，c； c，d--
I think you get the idea.
我想你应该已经明白了。
Just for completeness, V is a, b, c, d.
仅出于完整性考虑，V是a，b，c，d。
Just so you remember notations and so on.
只是您要记住符号等等。
One of the issues we're going to talk about in this class
我们将在本课程中讨论的问题之一
is how do you represent a graph like this for an algorithm?
怎样表示这样的图用于算法？
So it's all fine to say, oh, this is a set of things.
所以可以说，这是一堆事情。
This is a set of things.
这是一组事情。
An obvious representation is, you have
一个明显的表示是，
a list or an array of vertices.
列表或顶点数组。
You have an array of edges.
您有一组边线。
Each edge knows its two end points.
每个边都知道其两个端点。
That would be a horrible representation for a graph
这将是一个可怕的图形表示
because if you're, I don't know, at vertex, a,
因为如果你在顶点，我不知道
and you want to know, well what are the neighbors of a?
并且您想知道，a的邻居是什么？
b and c.
b和c。
You'd have to go through the entire edge list
您必须浏览整个边缘列表
to figure out the neighbors of a.
找出a的邻居。
So it's been linear time just to know where you can go from a.
所以这是线性的时间，只是要知道您可以从哪里去。
So we're not going to use that representation.
因此，我们将不使用该表示形式。
We're going to use some better representations.
我们将使用一些更好的表示形式。
Something called an adjacency list.
称为邻接表的东西。
Over here, you've got things like a, c; b, c; and c, b.
在这里，您会看到a，c之类的东西； b，c；和c，b。
So you can have edges in both directions.
因此，您可以在两个方向上都具有边缘。
What am I missing?
我想念什么？
b, a.
b，a
So that's E, in that case.
在这种情况下，那就是E。
There are a whole lot of applications of graph search.
图搜索有很多应用。
I'll make you a little list to talk about few of them.
我会列出一些清单，以供您讨论。
So we've got web crawling.
这样我们就可以进行网络爬网了。
You're Google.
您是Google。
You want to find all the pages on the web.
您要查找网络上的所有页面。
Most people don't just tell you, hey, I've got a new page,
大多数人不只是告诉你，嘿，我有一个新页面，
please index it.
请索引它。
You have to just keep following links--
您只需要保持以下链接-
in the early days of the web, this was a big deal--
在网络初期，这很重要-
following links finding everything that's out there.
以下链接可查找所有内容。
It's a little bit of an issue because if you define it wrong,
这是一个小问题，因为如果定义错误，
the internet is infinite because of all those dynamically
互联网是无限的，因为所有这些都是动态的
generated pages.
生成的页面。
But to deal with that, Google goes
但是为了解决这个问题，谷歌
sort of breadth-first for the most part.
大多数情况下，宽度优先。
It's prioritized You want to see all the things you
它是优先的您想看所有的东西
can reach from pages you already have and keep going.
可以从您已有的页面访问并继续前进。
At some point, you give up when you run out of time.
在某个时候，您会在时间用完时放弃。
Social networking.
社交网络。
You're on Facebook.
您正在使用Facebook。
You use Friend Finder.
您使用朋友查找器。
It tries to find the friends that are nearest to you.
它试图找到离您最近的朋友。
Or friends of friends is sort of a level to search.
或朋友的朋友是要搜索的级别。
That's essentially a graph search problem.
从本质上讲，这是一个图搜索问题。
You want to know what's two levels or three
您想知道两个或三个级别
levels of separation from you.
与您的分离水平。
And then you loop over those and look for other signs
然后遍历那些并寻找其他迹象
that you might be good friends.
你可能是好朋友。
You are on a network like the internet or some intranet.
您正在使用Internet或某些Intranet之类的网络。
You want to broadcast a message.
您要广播一条消息。
So here's you.
所以这是你。
You want to send data out.
您要发送数据。
That's essentially a graph exploration problem.
从本质上讲，这是一个图形探索问题。
That message, that packet, is going to explore the graph.
那个消息，那个数据包，将探索图。
Garbage collection.
垃圾收集。
I hope you all know that modern languages have
我希望大家都知道现代语言有
garbage collection.
垃圾收集。
This is why you don't have to worry about freeing things.
这就是为什么您不必担心释放东西的原因。
Even in Python-- even in CPython,
即使在Python中-甚至在CPython中，
I learned-- there is a garbage collector as of version two.
我了解到-从第二版开始就有一个垃圾收集器。
But also in PyPy, and JPython and in Java--
而且在PyPy，JPython和Java中-
pretty much every fairly modern language
几乎每种相当现代的语言
you have garbage collection.
你有垃圾收集。
Meaning, if there's some data that's unreachable from--
意思是，如果某些数据无法通过以下方式访问-
So you have your variables.
所以你有自己的变量。
Variables that can be accessed by the program.
程序可以访问的变量。
Everything that's reachable from there you have to keep.
从那里可以到达的一切都必须保留。
But if some data structure becomes no longer reachable,
但是，如果某些数据结构不再可访问，
you can throw it away and regain memory.
您可以扔掉它并重新获得记忆。
So that's happening behind the scenes all the time,
所以这一直在幕后发生，
and the way it's being done is with
它的完成方式是
their breadth-first search, which
他们的广度优先搜索
is what we're going to talk about today.
这就是我们今天要谈论的。
Another one.
另一个。
Model checking.
模型检查。
Model checking is-- you have some finite model of either
模型检查是-您可以选择其中一个的有限模型
a piece of code, or a circuit, or chip, whatever,
一段代码，电路，芯片等等
and you want to prove that it actually
你想证明它实际上
does what you think it does.
按照您的想法去做。
And so you've drawn a graph.
因此，您绘制了一个图形。
The graph is all the possible states
该图是所有可能的状态
that your circuit or your computer program could reach,
您的电路或计算机程序可以达到的目标
or that it could possibly have.
或者它可能有。
You start in some initial state, and you
您从某种初始状态开始，然后
want to know among all the states that you can reach,
想知道您可以达到的所有状态，
does it have some property.
它有一些属性吗？
And so you need to visit all the vertices that
因此，您需要访问所有的顶点
are reachable from a particular place.
可以从特定位置到达。
And usually people do that using breadth-first search.
通常人们使用广度优先搜索来做到这一点。
I use breadth-first search a lot,
我经常使用广度优先搜索，
myself, to check mathematical conjectures.
我自己，检查数学猜想。
So if you're a mathematician, and you think something
因此，如果您是数学家，并且您认为
is true.
是真的。
Like maybe-- It's hard to give an example of that.
也许-很难举一个例子。
But you can imagine some graph of all the possible inputs
但是您可以想象所有可能输入的一些图形
to that theorem, and you need to check them
那个定理，你需要检查一下
for every possible input--
对于每种可能的输入-
If this is true-- the typical way to do that
如果这是真的-这样做的典型方法
is breadth-first searching through that entire graph
在整个图上进行广度优先搜索
of states.
状态。
Usually, we're testing finite, special cases
通常，我们正在测试有限的特殊情况
of a general conjecture, but if we find a counter-example,
一般猜想，但是如果我们找到反例，
we're done.
我们完成了。
Don't have to work on it anymore.
不必再努力了。
If we don't find a counter-example, usually then
如果我们找不到反例，通常
we have to do the mathematics.
我们必须做数学。
It doesn't solve everything, but it's helpful.
它并不能解决所有问题，但很有帮助。
And then, the fun thing we're going
然后，我们要做的有趣的事情
to talk about a little bit today,
今天要谈一点
is if you want to solve something like a two
如果你想解决两个问题
by two by two Rubik's Cube optimally,
最佳地乘以二乘两的魔方，
you can do that using breadth-first search.
您可以使用广度优先搜索来做到这一点。
And you're going to do that on your problem set.
您将在问题集上进行此操作。
To do it solving this one optimally using breadth-first
要做到这一点，最好使用广度优先
search would probably--
搜索可能-
would definitely-- take more than the lifetime
肯定会-花一生以上的时间
of the universe.
宇宙
So don't try seven by seven by seven.
所以不要尝试七乘七乘七。
Leave that to the cubing experts, I guess.
我猜这要留给相关专家。
I think no one will ever solve a seven by seven by seven
我认为没人会以七乘七的比例解决问题
Rubik's Cube optimally.
魔方最佳。
There are ways to find a solution just not the best one.
有很多方法不能找到最佳解决方案。
So let me tell you just for fun, as an example.
因此，让我告诉您一个很好的例子。
This Pocket Cube, which is a two by two by two Rubik's Cube.
这个袖珍立方体，是一个两乘两乘的魔方。
What we have in mind is called the configuration graph
我们想到的就是配置图
or sometimes configuration space.
或有时配置空间。
But it's a graph, so we'll call it a graph.
但这是一个图形，因此我们将其称为图形。
This graph has a vertex for each possible state of the cube.
该图为多维数据集的每个可能状态都有一个顶点。
So this is a state.
所以这是一个状态。
This is a state.
这是一种状态。
Now I'm hopelessly lost.
现在我无可救药地迷路了。
Anyone want to work on this?
有人要为此工作吗？
Bored?
无聊？
No one?
没有人？
Alright, I'll leave it unsolved then.
好吧，那我就把它解决掉。
So all those are vertices.
所以所有这些都是顶点。
There's actually a lot of vertices.
实际上有很多顶点。
There are 264 million vertices or so.
大约有2.64亿个顶点。
If you want.
如果你想。
To the side here.
在这边
Number of vertices is something like 8 factorial times 3
顶点数大约是8阶乘3
to the 8.
到8。
And one way to see that is to draw a two by two
看到它的一种方法是画一个二乘二
by two Rubik's Cube.
由两个魔方。
So these are what you might call cubelets,
这些就是您可能称为的多维数据集，
or cubies I think is the standard term in Rubik's Cube
我认为这是Rubik's Cube中的标准术语
land.
土地。
There's eight of them in a two by two by two.
一共有八乘二乘二乘。
Two cubed.
两个立方体。
You can essentially permute those cubies within the cube
您基本上可以在多维数据集中置换这些立方
however you like.
但是你喜欢。
That's 8 factorial.
那是8阶乘。
And then each of them has three possible twists.
然后它们每个都有三个可能的转折。
It could be like this.
可能是这样。
Or it could be like this.
或者可能是这样。
So you've got three for each.
因此，每个都有三个。
And this is actually an accurate count.
这实际上是一个准确的计数。
You're not over-counting the number of configurations.
您并没有过多地考虑配置数量。
All of those are, at least in principle, conceivable.
所有这些，至少在原则上都是可以想到的。
If you take apart the cube, you can reassemble it
如果拆开立方体，可以重新组装
in each of those states.
在每个州中。
And that number is about 264 million.
这个数字约为2.64亿。
Which is not so bad for computers.
这对于计算机来说还不错。
You could search that.
您可以搜索。
Life is a little bit easier.
生活要轻松一些。
You get to divide by 24 because there's
你除以24是因为
24 symmetries of the cube.
立方体的24个对称。
Eight times three.
八乘三。
You can divide by three, also, because only a third
您也可以除以三，因为只有三分之一
of the configuration space is actually reachable.
配置空间实际上是可以到达的。
If you're not allowed to take the parts apart,
如果您不允许拆开零件，
if you have to get there by a motion,
如果您必须动身到达那儿，
you can only get to 1/3 of the two by two by two.
您只能乘以2乘以2乘以1/3。
So it's a little bit smaller than that,
所以比这小一点
if you're actually doing a breadth-first search, which
如果您实际上是在进行广度优先搜索，
is what you're going to be doing on your problem set.
这就是您要解决的问题所在。
But in any case, it's feasible.
但是无论如何，这都是可行的。
That was vertices.
那是顶点。
We should talk about edges.
我们应该谈论边缘。
For every move-- every move takes you
每一步-每一步都需要您
from one configuration to another.
从一种配置到另一种。
You could traverse it in one direction and make that move.
您可以朝一个方向移动它并进行移动。
You could also undo that move.
您也可以撤消该动作。
Because every move is undoable in a Rubik's Cube,
因为在魔方中每一步都是不可挽回的，
this graph is undirected.
该图是无向的。
Or you can think of it as every edge works in both directions.
或者，您可以考虑一下它，因为每个边缘都在两个方向上起作用。
So this is a move.
所以这是一个举动。
It's called a quarter twist.
这叫做四分之一转。
This is a controversy if you will.
如果您愿意，这是一个争议。
Some people allow a whole half twist as a single move.
有些人只允许单步移动一半。
Whether you define that as a single move or a double move
您将其定义为单举还是双举
is not that big a deal.
没什么大不了的。
It just changes some of the answers.
它只是改变了一些答案。
But you're still exploring essentially the same graph.
但是您仍在探索基本相同的图。
So that's the graph and you'd like
这就是图表，您想要
to know some properties about it.
了解它的一些属性。
So let me draw a picture of the graph.
因此，让我画一幅图。
I'm not going to draw all 264 million vertices.
我不会绘制所有2.64亿个顶点。
But in particular, there's the solved state--
但特别是有一个已解决的状态-
we kind of care about that one, where
我们有点在意那个
all the colors are aligned--
所有颜色都对齐了
then there's all of the configurations
然后有所有的配置
you could reach by one move.
一口气就能到达。
So these are the possible moves from the solved state.
因此，这是从已解决状态可能采取的行动。
And then from those configurations,
然后从这些配置中
there's more places you can go.
还有更多可以去的地方。
Maybe there's multiple ways to get to the same node.
也许有多种方法可以到达同一个节点。
But these would be all the configurations
但是这些就是所有的配置
you can reach in two moves.
您可以分两步到达。
And so on.
等等。
And at some point, you run out of graph.
在某些时候，您用光了图表。
So there might be a few nodes out here.
因此，这里可能有几个节点。
The way I'm drawing this, this is everything
我画这个的方式，这就是一切
you can reach in one move, in two movies, in three moves.
您可以一招，两部电影，三招。
At the end, this would be 11 moves,
最后，这将是11个动作
if you allow half twists.
如果允许半曲。
And as puzzlers, we're particularly
作为困惑者，我们特别
interested in this number, which you
对这个号码感兴趣，你
would call, as a graph theorist, the diameter of the graph.
作为图论者，将称为图的直径。
Puzzlers call it God's number.
困惑者称其为上帝的数字。
If you were God or some omni--
如果您是上帝或一些全能的人，
something being.
某事。
You have the optimal algorithm for solving the Rubik's Cube.
您拥有解决魔方的最佳算法。
How many moves do you need If you always
您需要多少步，如果您总是
follow the best path?
走最好的路？
And the answer is, in the worst case, 11.
答案是在最坏的情况下为11。
So we're interested in the worst case of the best algorithm.
因此，我们对最佳算法的最坏情况感兴趣。
For two by two by two, the answer is 11.
对于二乘二乘二，答案是11。
For three by three by three, the answer is 20.
对于三乘三乘三，答案是20。
That was just proved last summer with a couple
去年夏天，一对夫妇证明了这一点
years of computer time.
年的计算机时间。
For four by four by four--
四乘四乘四
I don't have one here--
我这里没有一个
I think we'll never know the answer.
我想我们永远不会知道答案。
For five by five by five, we'll never know the answer.
对于五乘五乘五，我们永远不会知道答案。
For six, for seven, same deal.
六个，七个，同样的交易。
But for two by two by two, you can compute it.
但是对于二乘二乘二，您可以计算出来。
You will compute it on your problem set.
您将根据自己的问题集进行计算。
And it's kind of nice to know because it
很高兴知道
says whatever configuration I'm in, I can solve it in 11 moves.
说我所使用的任何配置，我都可以在11个步骤中解决。
But the best known way to compute it,
但是最著名的计算方法
is basically to construct this graph one layer at a time
基本上是一次构造该图
until you're done.
直到完成。
And then you know what the diameter is.
然后您知道直径是多少。
The trouble is, in between here this grows exponentially.
问题是，在这之间，它成倍增长。
At some point, it decreases a little bit.
在某些时候，它会减少一点。
But getting over that exponential hump
但是克服那指数的驼峰
is really hard.
真的很难
And for three by three by three, they used a lot of tricks
而三乘三乘三，他们使用了很多技巧
to speed up the algorithm, but in the end
加快算法，但最终
it's essentially a breadth-first search.
这本质上是广度优先的搜索。
What's a breadth-first search?
什么是广度优先搜索？
This going layer by layer.
这层层走。
So we're going to formalize that in a moment.
因此，我们暂时将其正式化。
But that is the problem.
但这就是问题所在。
So just for fun, any guesses what
所以只是为了好玩，任何猜测
the right answer is for an n by n by n Rubik's cube?
正确的答案是对于一个n×n×n的Rubik立方体？
What's the diameter?
直径是多少？
Not an exact answer, because I think we'll never
没有确切的答案，因为我认为我们永远不会
know the exact answer.
知道确切的答案。
But if I want theta something, what
但是如果我想要theta，那
do you think the something is?
你认为这是什么吗？
How many people here have solved the Rubik's Cube?
这里有多少人解决了魔方魔方？
Ever?
曾经吗
So you know what we're talking about here.
所以您知道我们在这里谈论什么。
Most people have worked on it.
大多数人都在为此工作。
To think about an n by n by n Rubik's Cube,
想一想n by n Rubik's Cube，
each side has area n squared.
每边的面积为n平方。
So total surface area is 6 n squared.
因此，总表面积为6 n平方。
So there's, roughly, stata n squared little cubies here.
因此，这里大约有方形的小立方体。
So what do you think the right [INAUDIBLE] is for n by n by n?
那么您认为正确的[音频不清晰]是n×n×n的呢？
No guesses?
没猜到吗？
AUDIENCE: n cubed?
听众：n立方？
PROFESSOR: n cubed?
教授：n立方？
Reasonable guess.
合理的猜测。
But wrong.
但是错了。
It's an upper bounds.
这是一个上限。
Why n cubed?
为什么n立方？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Oh, you're guessing based on the numbers.
教授：哦，您是根据数字猜测的。
Yeah.
是的
The numbers are misleading, unfortunately.
不幸的是，数字令人误解。
It's the law of small numbers I guess.
我猜这是小数定律。
It doesn't really look right.
看起来并不正确。
I know the answer.
我知道答案。
I know the answer because we just
我知道答案，因为我们只是
wrote a paper with the answer.
用答案写了一篇论文。
This is a new result. From this summer.
这是一个新结果。从今年夏天开始。
But I'm curious.
但是我很好奇。
To me the obvious answer is n squared because there's
对我来说，显而易见的答案是n平方，因为
about n squared cubies.
大约n个平方的立方。
And it's not so hard to show in a constant number moves
而且显示恒定数量的移动并不难
you can solve a constant number of cubies.
您可以解决恒定数量的Cubis。
If you think about the general algorithms,
如果您考虑一般算法，
like if you've ever looked up professor's cube
就像你曾经看过教授的立方体
and how to solve it, you're doing like 10 moves,
以及解决方法，您正在做10招，
and then maybe you swap two cubies
然后也许您交换了两个cubics
which you can use to solve a couple of cubies
您可以用来解决几个问题
in a constant number of moves.
以恒定的步伐移动。
So n squared would be the standard answer
所以n平方将是标准答案
if you're following standard algorithms.
如果您遵循标准算法。
But it turns out, you can do a little bit better.
但事实证明，您可以做得更好。
And the right answer is n squared divided by log n.
正确的答案是n平方除以log n。
I think it's cool.
我觉得很酷。
Hopefully, you guys can appreciate that.
希望你们能体会到这一点。
Not a lot of people can appreciate n squared divided
没有多少人可以欣赏n平方除法
by log n, but here in algorithms, we're all about n
通过log n，但是在算法中，我们都是关于n
squared over log n.
平方对数n。
If you're interested, the paper's on my website.
如果您有兴趣，可以在我的网站上找到该论文。
I think its called, Algorithms For Solving Rubik's Cubes.
我认为它的名字叫“解决魔方的算法”。
There's a constant there.
那里有一个常数。
Current constant is not so good.
电流常数不是很好。
Let's say it's in the millions.
假设它以百万计。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
You've got to start somewhere.
您必须从某个地方开始。
The next open problem will be to improve
下一个开放的问题将是改善
that constant to something reasonable that
恒定的东西
maybe is close to 20.
也许接近20。
But we're far from that.
但是，我们远非如此。
Let's talk about graph representation.
让我们谈谈图形表示。
Before we can talk about exporting a graph,
在我们讨论导出图形之前，
we need to know what we're given as input.
我们需要知道输入的内容。
And there's basically one standard representation
基本上有一个标准表示
and a bunch of variations of it.
和它的许多变化。
And they're called adjacency lists.
它们被称为邻接表。
So the idea with an adjacency list,
所以有一个邻接表的想法，
is you have an array called Adj, for adjacency
您是否有一个名为Adj的数组，用于邻接
of size V. Each element in the array
大小为V。数组中的每个元素
is a pointer to a linked list.
是指向链表的指针。
And the idea is that this array is indexed by a vertex.
想法是该数组由顶点索引。
So we're imagining a world where we
所以我们正在想象一个世界
can index arrays by vertices.
可以按顶点索引数组。
So maybe, you just label your vertices
所以也许，您只标记顶点
zero through v minus 1.
零到v减去1。
Then that's a regular array.
那是一个常规数组。
Or, if you want to get fancy, you
或者，如果您想花哨，
can think of a vertex as an arbitrary hashable thing,
可以将顶点视为任意可哈希的事物，
and Adj is actually a hash table.
而Adj实际上是一个哈希表。
And that's how you probably do it in Python.
这就是您可能在Python中执行的方式。
Maybe your vertices are objects, and this is just
也许您的顶点是对象，这仅仅是
hashing based on the address of the object.
根据对象的地址进行哈希处理。
But we're not going to worry about that.
但是我们不会为此担心。
We're just going to write Adj of u.
我们将要写您的Adj。
Assume that somehow you can get to the linked list
假设您可以通过某种方式进入链接列表
corresponding to that vertex.
对应于该顶点。
And the idea is, for every vertex
想法是，对于每个顶点
we just store its neighbors, namely
我们只是存储它的邻居，即
the vertices you can reach by one step from u.
您可以从u一步到达的顶点。
So I'm going to define that a little more formally.
因此，我将对此进行更正式的定义。
Adj of u is going to be the set of all vertices,
u的调整将是所有顶点的集合，
V, such that u, v is an edge.
V，这样u，v是边。
So if I have a vertex like b, Adj of b
所以如果我有一个像b这样的顶点
is going to be both a and c because in one step
将同时是a和c，因为一步
there are outgoing edges from b to a and b to c.
从b到a以及b到c有出射边。
So Adj of b is a, c.
所以b的Adj是a，c。
In that graph.
在那个图中。
I should have labeled the vertices something different.
我应该给顶点标注一些不同的东西。
Adj of a is going to be just c because you can't
A的调整将只是c，因为您不能
get with one step from a to b.
从a到b迈出一步。
The edge is in the wrong direction.
边缘方向错误。
And Adj of c is b.
c的调整是b。
I think that definition's pretty clear.
我认为这个定义很明确。
For undirected graphs, you just put braces here.
对于无向图，您只需在此处放括号。
Which means you store--
这意味着您存储-
I mean, it's the same thing.
我的意思是，这是同一回事。
Here Adj of c is going to be a, b, and d, as you
这里的c的调整将是a，b和d
can get in one step from c to a, from c to b, from c to d.
从c到a，从c到b，从c到d可以一步到位。
For pretty much every--
几乎每个
At least for graph exploration problems,
至少对于图探索问题，
this is the representation you want.
这是您想要的表示形式。
Because you're at some vertex, and you want to know,
因为您在某个顶点，并且您想知道，
where can I go next.
我下一步可以去哪里。
And Adj of that vertex tells you exactly where you can go next.
该顶点的Adj会告诉您确切的下一步。
So this is what you want.
这就是您想要的。
There's a lot of different ways to actually implement
实际上有很多不同的方法
adjacency lists.
邻接表。
I've talked about two of them.
我已经讨论了其中两个。
You could have the vertices labeled zero to v minus 1,
您可以将顶点标记为0到v减去1，
and then this is, literally, an array.
然后，这实际上是一个数组。
And you have--
你有 -
I guess I should draw.
我想我应该画画。
In this picture, Adj is an array.
在这张照片中，Adj是一个数组。
So you've got a, b, and c.
这样您就有了a，b和c。
Each one of them is a pointer to a linked list.
它们每个都是指向链接列表的指针。
This one's actually going to be a, c, and we're done.
这个实际上是a，c，我们完成了。
Sorry, that was b.
抱歉，那是b。
Who said it had to be alphabetical order?
谁说这必须是字母顺序？
A is a pointer to c, c is a pointer to b.
A是指向c的指针，c是指向b的指针。
That's explicitly how you might represent it.
这就是您可能如何表示的方式。
This might be a hash table instead of an array,
这可能是哈希表而不是数组，
if you have weirder vertices.
如果您有怪异的顶点。
You can also do it in a more object-oriented fashion.
您也可以以更面向对象的方式进行操作。
For every vertex, v, you can make the vertices objects,
对于每个顶点v，您都可以创建顶点对象，
and v dot neighbors could store what
V点邻居可以存储什么
we're defining over there to be Adj
我们在那边定义为Adj
of v. This would be the more object-oriented way to do it
v。这将是更面向对象的方法
I've thought a lot about this, and I like this,
我已经考虑了很多，我喜欢
and usually when I implement graphs this is what I do.
通常，当我实现图形时，这就是我要做的。
But it is actually convenient to have this representation.
但是实际上有这种表示很方便。
There's a reason the textbook uses this representation.
教科书使用这种表示形式是有原因的。
Because, if you've already got some vertices lying around
因为，如果您已经有一些顶点在附近
and you want to have multiple graphs on those vertices,
并且您想要在这些顶点上有多个图，
this lets you do that.
这可以让您做到这一点。
You can define multiple Adj arrays, one for graph one, one
您可以定义多个Adj数组，一个用于图一，一个
for graph two, one for graph three
对于图二，对于图三
but they can all talk about the same vertices.
但是他们都可以谈论相同的顶点。
Whereas here, vertex can only belong to one graph.
而在这里，顶点只能属于一个图形。
It can only have one neighbor structure
它只能有一个邻居结构
that says what happens.
那说明发生了什么。
If you're only dealing with one graph,
如果您只处理一张图，
this is probably cleaner.
这可能更干净。
But with multiple graphs, which will happen even in this class,
但是有了多个图，即使在此类中也会发生这种情况，
adjacency lists are kind of the way to go.
邻接表是一种处理方式。
You can also do implicitly-represented graphs.
您也可以做隐式表示的图。
Which would be to say, Adj of u is a function.
也就是说，u的Adj是一个函数。
Or v dot neighbors is a method of the vertex class.
或v点邻居是顶点类的一种方法。
Meaning, it's not just stored there explicitly.
意思是，它不只是显式地存储在那里。
Whenever you need it, you call this function
无论何时需要，都可以调用此函数
and it computes what you want.
并计算出您想要的
This is useful because it uses less space.
这很有用，因为它使用的空间更少。
You could say this uses zero space or maybe v space.
您可以说这使用零空间或v空间。
One for each vertex.
每个顶点一个。
It depends.
这取决于。
Maybe you don't even need to explicitly represent
也许您甚至不需要明确表示
all the vertices.
所有的顶点。
You start with some vertex, and given a vertex, somehow
您从某个顶点开始，然后以某种方式给定一个顶点
you know how to compute, let's say in constant time or linear
您知道如何进行计算，例如恒定时间或线性
time or something, the neighbors of that vertex.
时间或某物，那个顶点的邻居。
And then from there, you can keep
然后从那里开始
searching, keep computing neighbors,
搜索，保持计算邻居，
until you find what you want.
直到找到想要的东西。
Maybe you don't have to build the whole graph,
也许您不必构建整个图形，
you just need to build enough of it until you find your answer.
您只需要构建足够的内容，直到找到答案。
Whatever answer you're searching for.
无论您要寻找什么答案。
Can you think of a situation where that might be the case?
您能想到这种情况吗？
Where implicit representation would be a good idea?
隐式表示哪里是个好主意？
Yes.
是。
Rubik's Cubes.
魔方。
They're really good.
他们真的很好。
I never want to build this space.
我永远不想建立这个空间。
It has a bajillion states.
它有一个十亿个州。
A bajillion vertices.
数以万计的顶点。
It would take forever.
这将永远。
There's more configurations of this cube
此多维数据集还有更多配置
than there are particles in the known universe.
比已知宇宙中的粒子还要多。
I just computed that in my head.
我只是在脑子里计算了一下。
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
I have done this computation recently,
我最近进行了此计算，
and for five by five by five it's like 10 to the 40 states.
五到五乘五代表40个州中的10个。
Or 10 to the 40, 10 to the 60.
或10到40，10到60。
There's about 10 to the 80 particles in the known
在已知的粒子中，大约有10到80个粒子
universe.
宇宙。
10 to the 83 or something.
10到83左右。
So this is probably 10 to the 200 or so.
因此，这大概是10到200左右。
It's a lot.
好多
You never want to build that.
您永远不需要构建它。
But, it's very easy to represent this state.
但是，很容易表示这种状态。
Just store where all the cubies are.
只需存储所有cubices所在的位置即可。
And it's very easy to see what are all the configurations you
而且很容易看到您的所有配置
can reach in one move.
一手就能达成。
Just try this move, try this move, try this move.
只需尝试此举，尝试此举，再尝试此举即可。
Put it back and try the next move.
放回去并尝试下一步。
And so on.
等等。
For an m by n by n cube in order n
对于m×n×n立方体，顺序为n
time, you can list all the order n next states.
时间，您可以列出所有n个下一个状态的命令。
You can list all the order n neighbors.
您可以列出所有n个邻居。
And so you can keep exploring, searching for your state.
因此，您可以继续探索，搜索状态。
Now you don't want to explore too far for that cube,
现在，您不想为那个立方体探索太多，
but at least you're not hosed just
但至少你不只是用软管
from the problem of representing the graph.
从表示图形的问题出发。
So even for two by two by two, it's
所以即使是二乘二乘
useful to do this mostly to save space.
这样做主要是为了节省空间。
You're not really saving time.
您并没有真正节省时间。
But you'd like to not have to store all 264 million states
但是您不必存储所有2.64亿个州
because it's going to be several gigabytes and it's annoying.
因为它将达到数GB，这很烦人。
Speaking of space-- ignoring the implicit representation--
说到空间-忽略隐式表示-
how much space does this representation require?
此表示需要多少空间？
V plus E. This Is going to be the bread and butter
V加E。这将成为面包和黄油
of our graph algorithms.
我们的图算法。
Most of the things we're going to talk about achieve V plus E
我们要谈论的大多数事情都达到V加E
time.
时间。
This is essentially optimal.
这本质上是最佳的。
It's linear in the size of your graph.
它在图形大小上是线性的。
You've got V vertices, E edges.
您有V个顶点，E个边。
Technically, in case you're curious,
从技术上讲，如果您感到好奇，
this is really the size of V plus the size of E.
这实际上是V的大小加上E的大小。
But in the textbook, and I guess in the world,
但是在教科书中，我想全世界
we just omit those sizes of whenever they're in a theta
我们只是忽略了它们在theta中的大小
notation or Big O notation.
标记或Big O标记。
So number vertices plus number of edges.
因此，顶点数加上边数。
that sort of the bare minimum you
那种最低限度的最低要求
need if you want an explicit representation of the graph.
如果需要图形的显式表示，则需要。
And we achieve that because we've
我们实现这一目标是因为我们已经
got we've got v space just to store the vertices in an array.
我们有v空间仅用于将顶点存储在数组中。
And then if you add up--
然后，如果您加起来-
Each of these is an edge.
这些都是优势。
You have to be a little careful.
你要小心点
In undirected graphs, each of these is a half edge.
在无向图中，每一个都是半边。
So there's actually two times e nodes over here.
因此，实际上这里有两个e节点。
But it's theta E. So theta V plus E
但这是thetaE。所以theta V加E
is the amount of space we need.
是我们需要的空间量。
And ideally, all our algorithms will run in this much time.
理想情况下，我们所有的算法都将在这么长时间内运行。
Because that's what you need just to look at the graph.
因为这就是您只需要查看图表所需要的。
So let's do an actual algorithm, which is breadth-first search.
因此，让我们做一个实际的算法，即广度优先搜索。
So to the simplest algorithm you can think of in graphs.
因此，对于最简单的算法，您可以在图形中想到。
I've already outlined it several times.
我已经概述了好几次了。
You start at some node.
您从某个节点开始。
You look at all the nodes you can get to from there.
您查看从那里可以到达的所有节点。
Keep going until you're done.
继续直到完成。
So this is going to explore all of the vertices that
因此，这将探索所有的顶点
are reachable from a node.
从一个节点可达。
The challenge-- The one annoying thing
挑战-一件事烦人
about breadth-first search and why this is not trivial
关于广度优先搜索的原因，以及为什么这样做并不简单
is that there can be some edges that
可能会有一些边缘
go sort of backwards, like that, to some previous layer.
像这样倒退到上一层。
Actually, that's not true, is it?
其实不是这样，是吗？
This can't happen.
这不可能发生。
You see why?
你明白为什么吗？
Because if that edge existed, then from this node
因为如果存在该边缘，则从该节点开始
you'd be able to get here.
您将能够到达这里。
So in an undirected graph, that can't happen.
因此，在无向图中不会发生这种情况。
In a directed graph, you could conceivably
在有向图中，可以想象
have a back edge like that.
有这样的后缘。
You'd have to realize, oh, that's a vertex I've already
您必须意识到，哦，这是我已经拥有的一个顶点
seen, I don't want to put it here, even though it's
看到了，即使它是
something I can reach from this node,
我可以从这个节点到达的东西
because I've already been there.
因为我已经去过那里。
We've got to worry about things like that.
我们必须担心这样的事情。
That's, I guess, the main thing to worry about.
我想这就是主要要担心的事情。
So our goal is to visit all the nodes--
所以我们的目标是访问所有节点
the vertices-- reachable from given node, s.
顶点-可从给定节点s到达。
We want to achieve V plus E time.
我们要达到V加E的时间。
And the idea is to look at the nodes that are
想法是看一下
reachable first in zero moves.
零移动中首先到达。
Zero moves.
零动。
That's s.
是的。
Then in one move.
然后一招。
Well that's everything you can reach from s in one step.
好了，一步就可以达到s的一切。
That's adjacency of s.
那是s的邻接。
And then two moves, and three moves, and so
然后是两个动作，三个动作，依此类推
on until we run out of graph.
直到我们用完图表。
But we need to be careful to avoid duplicates.
但是我们需要注意避免重复。
We want to avoid revisiting vertices
我们要避免重新访问顶点
for a couple of reasons.
有几个原因。
One is if we didn't, we would spend infinite time.
一是如果我们不这样做，我们将花费无限的时间。
Because we'd just go there and come back,
因为我们只是去那里再回来，
and go there and come back.
然后去那里再回来
As long as there's at least one cycle,
只要至少有一个周期，
you're going to keep going around the cycle
您将继续循环
forever and ever if you don't try to avoid duplicates.
如果您不尝试避免重复，那就永远。
So let me write down some code for this algorithm.
因此，让我为该算法写下一些代码。
It's pretty straightforward.
这很简单。
So straightforward, we can be completely explicit
非常简单，我们可以完全明确
and write pseudocode.
并编写伪代码。
There's a few different ways to implement this algorithm.
有几种不同的方法可以实现此算法。
I'll show you my favorite.
我会告诉你我的最爱。
The textbook has a different favorite.
教科书有不同的喜好。
I'm going to write in pure Python, I believe.
我相信，我将用纯Python编写。
Almost done.
快完成了
I think I got that right.
我想我没错。
So this is at the end of the while-loop.
因此，这是在while循环的结尾。
And at that point we should be done.
在这一点上，我们应该完成。
We can do an actual example, maybe.
我们可以做一个实际的例子。
I'm going to do it on an undirected graph,
我将在无向图上执行该操作
but this algorithm works just as well on directed and undirected
但是该算法在定向和无定向上同样有效
graphs.
图。
There's an undirected graph.
有一个无向图。
We're given some start vertex, s,
我们得到了一些起始顶点s
and we're given the graph by being
我们得到的图形是
given the adjacency lists.
给定邻接表。
So you could iterate over the vertices of that thing.
因此，您可以遍历该对象的顶点。
Given a vertex, you can list all the edges
给定一个顶点，您可以列出所有边缘
you can reach in one step.
您可以一步一步到达。
And then the top of the algorithm's
然后是算法的顶部
just some initialization.
只是一些初始化。
The basic structure--
基本结构
We have this thing called the frontier, which is what we just
我们有一个叫做边境的东西，这就是
reached on the previous level.
达到上一个级别。
I think that's going to be level i minus one.
我认为这将是我的水平减去一。
Just don't want to make an index error.
只是不想使索引错误。
These are going to be all the things you can reach using
这些将是您可以使用的所有东西
exactly i minus one moves.
我恰好减去一招。
And then next is going to be all the things
接下来就是所有的东西
you can reach in i moves.
你可以达到我的举动。
So to get started, what we know is s.
因此，开始之前，我们知道的是s。
s is what you can reach in zero moves.
s是您零移动即可达到的目标。
So we set the level of s to be zero.
因此，我们将s的级别设置为零。
That's the first line of the code.
那是代码的第一行。
There's this other thing called the parent.
还有另一件事叫父母。
We'll worry about that later.
我们稍后会担心。
It's optional.
它是可选的。
It gives us some other fun structure.
它为我们提供了其他有趣的结构。
We set i to be one because we just finished level zero.
我们将i设为1，因为我们刚完成零级。
Frontier of what you can reach in level zero is just s itself.
您可以在零级达到的范围的边界本身就是s。
So we're going to put that on the list.
因此，我们将其列入清单。
That is level zero. i equals one So one minus one is zero.
那是零级。我等于一，所以一减一等于零。
All good.
都好。
And then we're going to iterate.
然后我们要进行迭代。
And this is going to be looking at--
而这将会是
The end of the iteration is to increment i.
迭代的结尾是增加i。
So you could also call this a for-loop
因此，您也可以将其称为for循环
except we don't know when it's going to end.
除了我们不知道什么时候结束。
So it's easier to think of i incrementing
因此，考虑到我增加时会更容易
each step not knowing when we're going to stop.
每个步骤都不知道我们何时要停止。
We're going to stop whenever we run out of nodes.
每当节点用完时，我们都将停止。
So whenever frontier is a non-empty list.
因此，只要边界是一个非空列表。
the bulk of the work here is computing
这里的大部分工作是计算
what the next level is.
下一个级别是什么。
That's called next.
那就是下一个。
It's going to be level i.
这将是我的水平。
We do some computation.
我们进行一些计算。
Eventually we have what's on the next level.
最终，我们有了下一个层次。
Then we set frontier next.
然后我们接下来设置边界。
Because that's our new level.
因为那是我们的新水平。
We increment i, and then invariant of frontier being
我们递增i，然后边界一直不变
level i minus 1 is preserved.
级别i减去1被保留。
Right after here.
就在这里。
And then we just keep going till we run out of nodes.
然后，我们一直继续直到节点用尽。
How do we compute next?
接下来如何计算？
Well, we look at every node in the frontier,
好吧，我们看一下边界中的每个节点，
and we look at all the nodes you can reach from those nodes.
然后我们查看您可以从这些节点到达的所有节点。
So every node, u, in the frontier and then we look at--
因此，您在边界中的每个节点，然后我们来看……
So this means there is an edge from u
所以这意味着你有优势
to v through the picture.
穿过图片。
We look at all the edges from all the frontier nodes
我们查看所有边界节点的所有边缘
where you can go.
你可以去哪里。
And then the key thing is we check for duplicates.
然后关键是我们要检查重复项。
We see, have we seen this node before?
我们知道，我们以前见过这个节点吗？
If we have, we would have set it's level to be something.
如果有的话，我们应该将它的级别设置为某种程度。
If we haven't seen it, it will not
如果我们没有看到它，它将不会
be in the level hash table or the level dictionary.
在级别哈希表或级别字典中。
And so if it's not in there, we'll put it in there
因此，如果它不在其中，我们将其放入其中
and add it to the next layer.
并将其添加到下一层。
So that's how you avoid duplicates.
这样便可以避免重复。
You set its level to make sure you will never visit it again,
您设置其级别以确保您再也不会访问它，
you add it to the next frontier, you iterate, you're done.
您将其添加到下一个边界，进行迭代，就完成了。
This is one version of what you might
这是您可能会遇到的一个版本
call a breadth-first search.
进行广度优先搜索。
And it achieves this goal, visiting
它实现了这一目标，
all the nodes reachable from s, in linear time.
所有节点从s到线性时间。
Let's see how it works on a real example.
让我们看看它是如何在一个真实示例中工作的。
So first frontier is this thing.
所以这是最前沿的事情。
Frontier just has the node s, so we just look at s,
边境只有节点s，所以我们只看s，
and we look at all the edges from s.
然后我们查看s的所有边。
We get a and x.
我们得到a和x。
So those get added to the next frontier.
因此，这些将被添加到下一个领域。
Maybe before I go too far, let me switch colors.
也许在我走得太远之前，让我切换颜色。
Multimedia here.
多媒体在这里。
So here's level one.
所以这是第一层。
All of these guys, we're going to set their level to one.
所有这些人，我们将其级别设置为1。
They can be reached in one step.
一步就可以达到。
That's pretty clear.
很清楚
So now frontier is a and x.
所以现在边界是a和x。
That's what next becomes.
这就是接下来的事情。
Then frontier becomes next.
然后边界成为下一个。
And so we look at all the edges from a.
因此，我们从a看所有边缘。
That's going to be s and z.
那将是s和z。
s, we've already looked at, it already has a level set,
s，我们已经看过了，已经设置了一个级别，
so we ignore that.
所以我们忽略了这一点。
So we look at z.
因此，我们看z。
Z does not have a level indicated here,
Z没有此处指示的水平，
so we're going to set it to i which happens
所以我们将其设置为i
to be two at this point.
在这一点上要成为两个。
And we look at x.
我们看x。
It has neighbors s, d, and c.
它具有邻居s，d和c。
We look at s again.
我们再次看s。
We say, oh, we've already seen that yet again.
我们说，哦，我们已经再次看到了。
So we're worried about this taking a lot of time
所以我们担心这会花费很多时间
because we look at s three times in total.
因为我们总共看了s三次。
Then we look at d.
然后我们看d。
d hasn't been set, so we set it to two. c hasn't been set,
d尚未设置，因此我们将其设置为2。尚未设置c
so we set it to two.
所以我们将其设置为两个。
So the frontier at level two is that.
因此，在第二级的前沿是。
Then we look at all the neighbors of z.
然后我们看z的所有邻居。
There's a. a's already been set.
有个。已经设置好了。
Look at all the neighbors of d.
看看d的所有邻居。
There's x.
有x。
There's c.
有c。
Those have been set.
那些已经设置好了。
There's f.
有f。
This one gets added.
这被添加。
Then we look at c.
然后我们看c。
There's x.
有x。
That's been done. d's been done.
已经做完了。 d完成了。
f's been done.
f已经完成。
v has not been done.
v尚未完成。
So this becomes a frontier at level three.
因此，这成为第三级的前沿。
Then we look at level three.
然后我们看三级。
There's f.
有f。
D's been done, c's been done, b's been done.
D已经完成，c已经完成，b已经完成。
We look at v. c's been done. f's been done.
我们来看v。c已经完成了。 f已经完成。
Nothing to add to next.
没有要添加的内容。
Next becomes empty.
下一步变为空。
Frontier becomes empty.
边界变空了。
The while-loop finishes.
while循环结束。
TA DA!
塔达！
We've computed-- we've visited all the vertices.
我们已经计算-我们已经访问了所有顶点。
Question.
题。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
What notation?
什么符号？
PROFESSOR: This is Python notation.
教授：这是Python表示法。
You may have heard of Python.
您可能听说过Python。
This is a dictionary which has one key value,
这是一本字典，只有一个键值，
s, and has one value, zero.
s，并且有一个值，零。
So you could--
所以你可以-
That's shorthand in Python for--
这是Python的简写-
Usually you have a comma separated list.
通常，您有一个用逗号分隔的列表。
The colon is specifying key value pairs.
冒号指定键值对。
I didn't talk about parent.
我没有谈论父母。
We can do that for a little bit.
我们可以做一点。
So parent we're initializing to say, the parent of s is nobody,
所以我们要初始化为parent，s的父母是没人，
and then whenever we visit a new vertex,
然后每当我们访问一个新顶点时，
v, we set its parent to be the vertex that we came from.
v，我们将其父级设为我们来自的顶点。
So we had this vertex, v. We had an edge
所以我们有这个顶点v。我们有一个优势
to v from some vertex, u.
从某个顶点到v
We set the parent of v to be u.
我们将v的父级设置为u。
So let me add in what that becomes.
因此，让我补充一下。
I'll change colors yet again.
我将再次更改颜色。
Although it gets hard to see any color but red.
虽然很难看到红色以外的任何颜色。
So we have s.
所以我们有。
When we visited a, then the parent of a would become s.
当我们访问a时，a的父代将变为s。
When we visited z, the parent of z would be a.
当我们访问z时，z的父代将是a。
Parent of x is going to be s.
x的父级将是s。
Parent of d is going to be x.
d的父级将是x。
The parent of c is going to be x.
c的父级将是x。
The parent of f--
f的父
it could have been either way, but the way I did it,
可以是任何一种方式，但是我这样做的方式，
d went first, and so that became its parent.
d首先进入，因此成为其父项。
And I think for v, c was its parent.
我认为对于v，c是其父代。
So that's what the parent pointers will look like.
这就是父指针的样子。
They always follow edges.
他们总是跟随边缘。
They actually follow edges backwards.
他们实际上向后跟随边缘。
If this was a directed graph, the graph
如果这是有向图，则该图
might be directed that way but the parent pointers
可能以这种方式指向，但父指针
go back along the edges.
沿着边缘往回走。
So it's a way to return.
因此，这是一种返回的方式。
It's a way to return to s.
这是返回s的一种方式。
If you follow these pointers, all roads lead to s.
如果遵循这些指针，则所有道路均通向s。
Because we started at s, that's the property we have.
因为我们从s开始，所以这就是我们的财产。
In fact, these pointers always form a tree,
实际上，这些指针总是形成一棵树，
and the root of the tree is s.
树的根是s。
In fact, these pointers form what are called shortest paths.
实际上，这些指针形成了所谓的最短路径。
Let me write down a little bit about this.
让我写下一点。
Shortest path properties.
最短路径属性。
If you take a node, and you take its parent,
如果您采用一个节点，并且采用其父节点，
and you take the parent of the parent,
然后您选择父母的父母，
and so on, eventually you get to s.
依此类推，最终您到达s。
And if you read it backwards, that will actually
如果您向后阅读，实际上
be a path in the graph.
是图中的路径。
And it will be a shortest path, in the graph,
在图中，这将是一条最短的路径，
from s to v. Meaning, if you look
从s到v。含义，如果您看
at all paths in the graph that go from s to v--
在图中从s到v的所有路径上-
So say we're going from s to v, how about that,
所以说我们要从s转到v，那怎么样，
we compute this path out of BFS.
我们从BFS中计算出该路径。
Which is, follow a parent of v is c, parent
就是说，跟随父的v是c，父
of c is x, parent of x is s.
c的x是x，x的父元素是s。
Read it backwards.
向后阅读。
That gives us a path from s to v.
这给了我们从s到v的路径。
The claim is, that is the shortest
索赔是，这是最短的
way to get from s to v. It might not be the only one.
从s到v的方法。它可能不是唯一的一种。
Like if you're going from s to f, there's two short paths.
就像您要从s转到f一样，这里有两条短路。
There's this one of length three.
这是长度三的之一。
There's this one of length three..
Uses three edges.
使用三个边缘。
Same length.
长度相同。
And in the parent pointers, we can only
在父指针中，我们只能
afford to encode one of those paths
能够编码其中一条路径
because in general there might be exponentially many ways
因为一般来说，可能有成倍的方式
to get from one node to another.
从一个节点到达另一个节点。
We find a shortest path, not necessarily the only one.
我们找到一条最短的路径，不一定是唯一的一条。
And the length of that path--
那条路的长度
So shortest here means that you use the fewest edges.
因此，这里最短意味着您使用的边最少。
And the length will be level of v. That's
长度将为v级。
what we're keeping track of.
我们正在跟踪的内容。
If the level's zero, you can get there with zero steps.
如果级别为零，则可以零级到达那里。
If the level's one, you get there with one steps.
如果是关卡，则只需一步即可到达。
Because we're visiting everything you can possibly
因为我们正在尽一切可能
get in k steps, the level is telling you what
进入k步，水平告诉您什么
that shortest path distance is.
最短的路径距离是。
And the parent pointers are actually
父指针实际上是
giving you the shortest path.
为您提供最短的路径。
That's the cool thing about BFS.
这就是BFS的酷之处。
Yeah, BFS explores the vertices.
是的，BFS探索顶点。
Sometimes, that's all you care about.
有时候，这就是您所关心的。
But in some sense, what really matters,
但是从某种意义上说，真正重要的是，
is it finds the shortest way to get from anywhere to anywhere.
它找到了从任何地方到任何地方的最快捷方法。
For a Rubik's Cube, that's nice because you
对于魔方来说，这很好，因为您
run BFS from the start state of the Rubik's Cube.
从魔方的开始状态运行BFS。
Then you say, oh, I'm in this state.
然后您说，哦，我处于这种状态。
You look up this state.
您查找此状态。
You look at its level.
您看一下它的水平。
It says, oh, you can get there in nine steps.
它说，哦，您可以按照以下九个步骤到达那里。
That's, I think, the average.
我认为这是平均值。
So I'm guessing.
所以我猜。
I don't know how to do this in nine steps.
我不知道如何通过九个步骤来执行此操作。
Great, so now you know how to solve it.
太好了，所以您现在知道如何解决它。
You just look at the parent pointer.
您只需查看父指针。
The parent pointer gives you another configuration.
父指针为您提供了另一种配置。
You say, oh, what move was that?
你说，哦，那是什么动作？
And then you do that move.
然后您执行此操作。
I'm not going to solve it.
我不会解决它。
Then you look at the parent pointer of that.
然后，您查看其父指针。
You do that move.
你这样做。
You look at the parent pointer of that.
您看一下它的父指针。
You do that move.
你这样做。
Eventually, you'll get to the solved state,
最终，您将达到解决状态，
and you will do it using the fewest possible moves.
并且您将使用最少的动作来完成。
So if you can afford to put the whole graph in memory, which
因此，如果您有能力将整个图形存储在内存中，
you can't for a big Rubik's Cube but you can for a small one,
您不能购买大型魔方，但可以购买小型魔方，
then this will give you a strategy, the optimal strategy,
那么这将为您提供一种策略，最佳策略，
God's algorithm if you will, for every configuration.
如果您愿意的话，可以针对每种配置使用上帝的算法。
It solves all of them.
它解决了所有这些问题。
Which is great.
太好了
What is the running time of this algorithm?
该算法的运行时间是多少？
I claim it's order V plus E. But it looked a little wasteful
我声称这是V加上E的订单。但是看起来有点浪费
because it was checking vertices over and over and over.
因为它一遍又一遍地检查顶点。
But if you think about it carefully,
但是如果仔细考虑一下
you're only looking--
你只是在看-
what's the right way to say this--
这样说的正确方法是-
you only check every edge once.
您只需检查每个边缘一次。
Or in undirected graphs, you check them twice,
或在无向图中，将它们检查两次，
once from each side.
每边一次。
A vertex enters the frontier only once.
顶点仅进入边界一次。
Because once it's in the frontier, it gets a level set.
因为一旦进入边界，就会获得一个等级集。
And once it has a level set, it'll never go in again.
设置了级别后，就再也不会进入了。
It'll never get added to next.
它永远不会添加到下一个。
So s gets added once then we check all the neighbors of s.
所以s被添加一次，然后我们检查s的所有邻居。
a gets added once, then we check all the neighbors of a.
将a添加一次，然后检查a的所有邻居。
Each of these guys gets added once.
这些家伙每个都被添加一次。
We check all the neighbors.
我们检查所有邻居。
So the total running time is going
所以总的运行时间在
to be the sum over all vertices of the size
是该大小的所有顶点的总和
of the adjacency list of v. So this is the number of neighbors
v的邻接列表。所以这是邻居的数量
that v has.
v有。
And this is going to be?
这将是？
Answer?
回答？
AUDIENCE: Two times the number of edges.
听众：边缘数量的两倍。
PROFESSOR: Sorry
教授：对不起
AUDIENCE: Double the number of edges.
听众：边缘数量加倍。
PROFESSOR: Twice the number of edges for undirected graphs.
教授：无向图的边数是原来的两倍。
It's going to be the number of edges for directed graphs.
这将是有向图的边数。
This is the Handshaking Lemma.
这就是握手引理。
If you don't remember the Handshaking Lemma,
如果您不记得握手引理，
you should read the textbook.
您应该阅读教科书。
Six o four two stuff.
六点四两的东西。
Basically you visit every edge twice.
基本上，您访问每个边缘两次。
For directed graphs, you visit every edge once.
对于有向图，您需要访问每个边一次。
But it's order E. We also spend order V
但这是订单E。我们也花了订单V
because we touch every vertex.
因为我们触摸每个顶点。
So the total running time is order V plus E.
因此，总运行时间为订单V加E。
In fact, the way this is going, you can be a little tighter
实际上，这样可以使您更加紧凑
and say it's order E. I just want to mention in reality--
并说它是E阶。我只想在现实中提到-
Sometimes you don't care about just what you can reach from s,
有时候，您并不只是在乎从s可以获得什么，
you really want to visit every vertex.
您真的想访问每个顶点。
Then you need another outer loop that's
然后您需要另一个外部循环
iterating over all the vertices as potential choices for s.
迭代所有顶点作为s的潜在选择。
And you then can visit all the vertices in the entire graph
然后，您可以访问整个图中的所有顶点
even if it's disconnected.
即使已断开连接。
We'll talk more about that next class.
我们将在下一堂课中进一步讨论。
That's it for BFS.
BFS就是这样。